Collectors 编译
船长！
Captain！
你究竟是谁？
Who are you？
加地斯，西班牙
这是怎么回事？
What is this？
国王陛下，他是被渔网捞上来的
Your Majesty，caught him up in a fishing net.
一个渔网
A fishing net.
陛下，他一直在讲故事
Sire，he's been telling stories.
故事说...
Stories that...
我们相信他找到了...
We believe he's found a...
庞塞德莱昂
Ponce de Leon.
说他找到庞塞德莱昂的船了
Says he found Ponce de Leon's ship.
或是搭过那艘船
Or sailed on it.
不，我跟你说过
No，I told you，
庞塞德莱昂死于两百年前
Ponce de Leon died 200 years ago.
但他死于寻找某样东西，对吧？
Aye，but he died searching for something，didn't he？
不老泉
The Fountain of Youth.
你航行可以多快？
How soon can you sail？
顺着海水潮汐
With the tide.
加勒比海盗 4：惊涛骇浪
在这里！幸运石楠！
Over here！Lucky heather！
伦敦，英格兰
海盗剑，海盗剑
Pirate swords！Pirate swords！
海盗今天绞刑
Pirate's execution today.
快来看他吊死！
Watch him swing！
海盗木偶！
Pirate puppets！
接招！
Take that，you！
爸爸，快点，不然看不到绞刑！
Hurry，Papa，or we'll miss the hanging！
不是绞刑，宝贝，是审讯
It's not a hanging，dear，it's a trial.
今天下午才是绞刑
The hanging comes this afternoon.
海盗今天被绞死！
Pirate hanging today！
起来，快点
Come on. Up you get.
海盗，向前走
Move along，pirate.
还是我应该说“海盗船长”？
Or should I say，“Captain Pirate”？
快点，走吧，往上走
Come on. Come on！Up you go.
肃静！秩序！
Quiet！Order！
肃静！
Quiet！
现在出庭的是
Now appearing before the court，
臭名昭著，声名狼藉的海盗，掠夺者
the notorious and infamous pirate，pillager，
和强盗...
and highwayman...
安静！
Quiet！
...杰克斯派罗船长！
...Captain Jack Sparrow！
我跟你们说过，我叫吉卜斯！
I told you，the name's Gibbs！
贾夏密吉卜斯！
Joshamee Gibbs！
要说几次...
How many times...
注意，注意！
Hear ye，hear ye！
主持这次审判
Presiding over these trials，
全体起立
all rise and attend，
尊敬的史密斯法官
the Right Honorable Justice Smith！
尊敬的阁下
My dear sir.
肃静！
Quiet！
现在...
Now...
...我们在这里做什么？
...what do we have here？
杰克？
Jack？
闭嘴！
Shut up！
我不认识他
I don't recognize him.
没有必要
Not necessary.
你要说什么？
You were saying？
我不是杰克斯派罗
Jack Sparrow is not my name.
我是贾夏密吉卜斯
My name is Joshamee Gibbs.
是这样吗？
Is that so？
这里说你是杰克斯派罗
It says Jack Sparrow here.
我跟他们说过
I told 'em.
我不是杰克斯派罗
I'm not Jack Sparrow，
如果有助于我的案子
who I would be happy to identify to the court
我很乐意当庭指认
if it would help my case.
这是拙劣的狡辩
I think that would be a poor defense，
除非你想要再挨棍子
unless you want to be bludgeoned again
像格陵兰海豹一样
like a harp seal.
犯人声称
The prisoner claims of being innocent
他不是杰克斯派罗
to being Jack Sparrow.
你们怎么判决？
How do you find？
不审判？
No trial？
不是该审查证据...
But aren't we here to examine the evidence...
陪审长，他有罪吗？
Foreman，your finding. Guilty？
有罪意味着他会被绞死
Guilty verdict means he'll hang.
绞死他！
Hang him！
把他吊起来！
String him up！
有罪？
Guilty？
这不公平！
That's not fair！
闭嘴
Shut it.
贾夏密吉卜斯
Joshamee Gibbs，
你被当成是杰克斯派罗
the crime of which you've been found guilty of
被判有罪是无罪的
is being innocent of being Jack Sparrow.
我在此改判你无期徒刑
I hereby commute your sentence，
待在监狱里
and order that you be imprisoned
度过你悲惨
for the remainder of your miserable，
垂死无助的余生
moribund，mutton-chopped life.
什么？
What？！
绞死他！
Hang him！
定谳
There.
胡言乱语！
Balderdash！
把他吊起来！
String him up！
绞死他！
Hang him high！
安排马车
Means shall be arranged
移送这名犯人
to transport this prisoner
到伦敦塔
to the Tower of London.
感激不尽
Thanks very much.
谢啦
Ta.
快点
Come on.
上车
Get up there.
上去！
Get up！
这下好了
Hell's teeth.
我们都进监狱了
Now we're both headed for prison.
不用担心
Not to worry.
我贿赂了车夫
I've paid off the driver.
十分钟后，我们会在伦敦城外
Ten minutes，we'll be outside London Town，
有马匹等着
horses waiting.
今晚，骑到海边
Tonight，we make the coast.
然后就是找一艘船的事了
Then it's just a matter of finding a ship.
一切都在计划中，是吧？
All part of the plan，yes？
没说错
Exactly.
今天一早我就来到伦敦城
I arrived in London Town just this morning
要从绞刑架
to rescue one Joshamee Gibbs
救出贾夏密吉卜斯
from one appointment with the gallows.
看到你还活着
Seeing as how you're still alive，
我会说到现在为止计划很成功
I'd say it's all been very successful thus far.
吉卜斯，你出什么事了？
What happened to you，Gibbs？
我以为你在别处工作
I thought you were employed elsewhere
或忙其他的
or otherwise engaged.
是啊，但我一直偷偷打听
Aye. But I always listened like a thief
黑珍珠号的消息
for news of the Black Pearl.
但没有人知道她停靠在哪个港口
Nobody's seen where she might next make port.
然后，我听到传闻：
Then，I hear a rumor:
杰克斯派罗带着船来伦敦
Jack Sparrow's in London with a ship
正在寻找船员
and looking for a crew.
哪有
Am not.
我听到的就是这些
But that's what I heard.
事实是
Fact is，
你今晚要签约雇用船员
you're signing up men tonight.
酒吧名字叫“船长的女儿”
Pub called The Captain's Daughter.
哪有
Am not！
是呀，我想这有点古怪
Well，I thought it a bit odd，
但是，你从不是最可预测的人
but then，you've never been the most predictable of sorts.
告诉我
Tell me something.
有另一个杰克斯派罗
There is another Jack Sparrow
在招摇撞骗？
out there sullying my good name？
冒牌货
An impostor.
没错
Indeed.
不过...
But...
是有一艘船的冒牌货
an impostor with a ship.
而且需要船员
And in need of a crew.
正巧，我也需要
Which，as fate would have it，so am I.
杰克，那你呢？
What about you，Jack？
上次我听说
Last I heard，
你拚命寻找不老泉
you were hell-bentto find the Fountain of Youth.
找到了？
Any luck？
发生要求有敏锐的洞察力
Circumstances arose and forced a compelling insight
关于谨慎以及勇气的情况
regarding discretion and valor.
意思是，你放弃了
Meaning，you gave up.
我没有
I did not.
我就和以前一样坚定
I am just as bent as ever.
非常坚定
Hellishly so.
我会喝到不老泉的，吉卜斯先生
I shall taste those waters，Master Gibbs.
记住我的话
Mark my words.
哦，这么快就到啦
Short trip.
一切都在计划中，是吧？
All part of the plan，yes？
不是
No.
你就是杰克斯派罗？
You are Jack Sparrow？
你忘了加上“船长”
There should be a“Captain”in there somewhere.
我听说过你
I've heard of you.
想必你知道我是谁
And you know who I am.
很面熟
Face is familiar.
我有恐吓过你？
Have I threatened you before？
在你面前的是
You are in the presence of
乔治奥古斯汀
George Augustus，
伯伦瑞克-吕讷堡公爵
Duke of Brunswick-Luneburg，
神圣罗马帝国的
Archtreasurer and Prince-elector
财务大臣和王子选侯
of the Holy Roman Empire，
英国和爱尔兰的国王
King of Great Britain and Ireland，
你的国王
and of you.
没听说过
Doesn't ring a bell.
我听说
I am informed
你是来伦敦
you have come to London to procure
招募船员
a crew for your ship.
邪恶的谣言，并非事实
Vicious rumor. Not true.
那你自称杰克斯派罗
Then you lied to me when you told me
就是骗我咯
you were Jack Sparrow.
我是杰克斯派罗
I am Jack Sparrow，
但我没有招募船员
but I'm not here to procure a crew.
那是...
That is...
另一个人
someone else.
另一个叫杰克斯派罗的人
Someone else named Jack Sparrow.
你们给我找错人了
You've brought me the wrong wastrel.
找到真的
Find the proper one
然后解决这个冒牌货
and dispose of this impostor.
不，等等
No，wait，wait，wait.
等一下
Hang on a minute.
我是杰克斯派罗
I'm Jack Sparrow，
独一无二
the one and only.
而且我在伦敦
And I am in London.
招募船员
To procure a crew.
准备启航
To undertake a voyage
前往不老泉...
to the Fountain...
你说什么？
What？
谁来拿掉那些
Will someone please remove these
讨厌的锁链？
infernal chains？
来，来
Come，come.
我们知道你有一张地图
We know you're in possession of a map.
没收地图
So confiscate the map，
然后绞死他
and to the gallows with him！
你有地图吗？
Have you a map？
没有
No.
地图在哪？
Where is it？
真相吗？
The truth？
我弄丢了
I lost it.
刚刚才弄丢的
Quite recently，in fact.
我收到一个情报
I have a report.
西班牙人找到不老泉了
The Spanish have located the Fountain of Youth.
我不会让忧郁的西班牙国王
I will not have some melancholy Spanish monarch，
一个天主教徒
a Catholic，
获得永生！
gain eternal life！
你知道不老泉怎么去吗？
You do know the way to the Fountain？
当然知道
Of course I do.
那我看
Look at me.
你可以率领探险队
You could guide an expedition.
陛下，如果您允许的话
With your permission，your heinie，
您会提供
you will be providing，then，
一艘船...
a ship...
...和船员？
...and a crew？
还有一位船长
And a captain.
午安，陛下
Afternoon，sire.
恕我大胆
If I may be so bold，
为什么那个人没上锁链？
why is that man not in chains？
请立刻给他上锁链
He must be manacled at once.
就在我的皇宫？
At the center of my palace？
想都别想
Hardly.
老巴
Hector.
多么高兴看到一个海盗改邪归正
How nice to see a fellow pirate make good of himself.
海盗？不对
Pirate？Nay.
是私掠船
Privateer.
在吾王权威和保护下
On a sanctioned mission under the authority
进行官方批准的任务
and protection of the Crown.
就算是，但首先
As may be，but first，
我的宝贝黑珍珠号呢？
what has become of my beloved Pearl？
我失去黑珍珠号也失去一条腿
I lost the Pearl as I lost my leg.
失去黑珍珠号？
Lost the Pearl？
对
Aye.
虽然我努力保卫她
I defended her mightily enough，
但她仍然沉入海底
but she be sunk nonetheless.
如果那艘船沉入海底
If that ship be sunk properly，
那么船长就该和她一起
you should be sunk with it.
巴船长
Captain Barbossa，
我们每拖延一秒
each second we tarry，
西班牙佬就把我们抛得老远
the Spanish outdistance us.
我有信心
I have every confidence
你会获胜
you will prevail
并获得爵位奖赏
and be rewarded with the high station
正如你想要的
you so desire.
陛下，能为您服务就够了
To serve doth suffice，sire.
你喔
You，sir，
堕落了
have stooped.
我们的砂时计几乎要漏完了
Jack，our sands be all but run.
何不加入赢家的行列？
Where's the harmin joining the winning side？
而且你会认识王公贵族
And you do meeta nicer class of person.
我一切都明白
I understand everything.
除了你为什么要戴假发
Except that wig.
他就要逃走了！
He's getting away！
拦住他！
Stop him！
Head him off！
不！拦住这个海盗！
No！Stop that pirate！
下来！
Come down！
他逃走了？
He escaped？
陛下，他逃不出我的手心
Leave it to me，sire.
守卫！
Guards！Guards！
武器准备好了！
Arms at ready！
是，长官！
Aye，sir！
找到他！
Find him！
谁捡到的就归谁！
Finders keepers！
在那里！
There！
就这样放过我啊？
Is that it？
停车！拦住马车！
Halt！Stop that carriage！
拦住他！
Head him off！
让开！
Out of the way！
拦住那个海盗！
Stop that pirate！
让开！
Move out of the way！
拦住那个家伙！
Stop that man！
别让他逃了！
Don't let him get away！
开枪！
Fire！
他快逃走了！
He's getting away！
追他！
After him！
拦住他！
Stop him！
追他！
After him！
邪恶的海盗
Filthy pirate.
嗨，小杰
Hello，Jackie.
嗨，老爸
Hello，Dad.
我听说你在招募船员
I heard you're putting together a crew.
真是人言可畏啊
If enough people keep saying it，it must be true.
我听说你要率领探险队去不老泉
I heard where you're headed The Fountain.
你去过那里？
Have you been there？
这张脸像去过？
Does this face look like it's been to the Fountain of Youth？
这里灯光不太好
Depends on the light.
孩子，要找到不老泉
Son，the Fountain.
必须有异教仪式用的东西
There'll be items required for the profane ritual.
两个圣盃
Two chalices.
在地图上有一个圣盃
On the map there was a chalice.
两个，银制的
Two，silver.
在庞塞德莱昂船上
From the Ponce de Leon ship.
两个你都要
You'll need both.
做什么？
For？
仪式
The ritual.
小杰，不要当笨蛋
Don't be a fool，Jackie.
启航前要了解每个细节
Find out every detail before you set sail.
哦，启航，我也很想
Oh，set sail. Love to.
但对于这点
But for that，
我可能需要一艘船
I may need a ship.
在那边的那些家伙
Those folk，over there，
他们有一艘船
they have a ship.
他们现在正和水手们签约
They're signing up sailors right now.
我的心被爱神一箭射中
My heart is pierced by Cupid
黄金在我眼中变成粪土
I disdain all glittering gold
小杰，还有最后一件事
And one last thing，Jackie.
不老泉是一个考验
The Fountain will test you.
记住我的话
Mark my words.
我的心被爱神一箭射中
My heart is pierced by Cupid
黄金在我眼中变成粪土
I disdain all glittering gold
从此没有什么能安慰我
There is nothing can console me
除了那个快乐勇敢的水手
But my jolly sailor bold
我听说你们在招募船员
I hear you be recruiting a crew.
对，没错
Aye. That is，
杰克斯派罗正在召募船员
Jack Sparrow be putting together a modest venture.
你好大胆，是不是？
You got some nerve，ain't ya？
竟敢穿成这样在这里出现？
Turning up here dressed like that？
你是什么东西，冒牌货？
What are you，some kind of impostor？
你看不出来我是谁？
Have you any idea who I am，mate？
喂，朋友们！
Oi，muckers！
这家伙忘记自己的名字了！
There's a bloke here what's forgotten his own name！
大伙们，我要跟斯派罗一起出航了
Lads，I'm sailing with Sparrow.
谁愿意请一名水手喝一杯？
Who'll buy a sailor a drink？
下一个是谁？
Who's next？
给我们多来一些
Bring us some more of those ones.
再来四份
Yeah，make it four.
你冒充我
You've stolen me，
我要揭穿你
and I'm here to take meself back.
停止这样做
Stop doing that.
世界上冒充我能这么像的只有一个人
Only one person alive knows that move.
我一直想这样做
Always wanted to do that.
嗨，安洁莉卡
Hello，Angelica.
嗨，杰克
Hello，Jack.
令你印象深刻吧？
Are you impressed？
有一次或两次我几乎杀了你
I think I almost killed you once or twice there.
这最真诚的奉承让我好感动
I'm touched at this most sincerest form of flattery.
但是为什么？
But why？
你是我唯一能冒充的海盗
You were the only pirate I thought I would pass for.
这不是恭维
That is not a compliment.
杰克，放心
Don't worry，Jack.
我早就原谅你了
I forgave you a long time ago.
为了什么？
For what？
因为我甩了你？
For leaving you？
回想一下吧，是我甩了你
Recall that I left you.
一个绅士不会介意女士的幻想
A gentleman allows a lady to maintain her fictions.
斯派罗，听着
Look，Sparrow.
我的水手们只要有钱拿
As long as my sailors get their money，
他们就愿意忍受各种
they're willing to put up with any number of
怪癖
peculiarities.
有一个怪癖我就无法忍受
There is one peculiarity with which I will not put up with.
冒充我就该是“杰克斯派罗船长”
I will be impersonated as“Captain”. Nothing less.
当船长还不简单，只要有一艘船
Well，for that，you need a ship，
而结果是，我就有一艘
and as it turns out，I have one.
我可以用这艘船
I could use a ship.
我听说你去过不老泉
I hear tell you've been to the Fountain.
最近几天道听途说真多
There be a lot of hear-telling going on these days.
不老泉
The Fountain of Youth.
亲爱的安洁莉卡，别担忧
Dearest Angelica，fret not.
你还要好几年才用得着
You still have a few usable years left.
总是那么会说话
Always so charming.
你还是没回答我
You didn't answer me.
关于不老泉
Aye. Regarding the Fountain.
浪费时间，真的...
Waste of time，really...
夫人，我看到像皇家海军的家伙进来了
Milady，I see unseamanlike fellows of an officious-looking nature.
卑鄙的海盗！找到他们！一群蛆！
Wretched pirates！Find 'em！Maggots！
你的朋友？
Friends of yours？
我可能无意中得罪了国王或其他
I may have unintentionally slighted some king or other.
开门！
Open it！
你真的是一点都没变
Yeah，you haven't changed.
是说我需要改变？
Implying the need？
是的
Yes.
快开门，奉国王陛下之名
Open this door，in the name of His Majesty.
你背弃了我
You betrayed me.
诱惑了我，还利用了我
You seduced me and you used me.
我当时还是个小姑娘
I was innocent of the ways of men.
我记得你还是个
You demonstrated a lot of technique
很多花招的小姑娘
for someone I supposedly corrupted.
快走啊
Imminent danger.
这里，快，夫人！
Here，now，milady！
开门！
Open it！
我原本是去修道院要当修女的
I was ready to take my vows.
而你...
And you...
你去西班牙女修道院找我干嘛？
What were you doing in a Spanish convent，anyway？
我弄错了以为是妓院
Mistook it for a brothel.
走错门了
Honest mistake.
他在这里
There he is！
在那
Over there！
我们处于不利地位
We are at a disadvantage.
是说你自己吧
Speak for yourself.
哪像某人只会冒充我
Unlike some who pretend to be，
却没有我厉害
but cannot，in fact，hold a candle to，
我才是杰克斯派罗船长
I am Captain Jack Sparrow.
你怎么能说我利用了你？
How can you say I used you？
你明白的很
You know exactly how.
我知道，但你怎么能这么说？
I know，but how can you say it？
怎么回事？
So，what is it？
什么怎么回事？
What is what？
不老泉啊
About the Fountain.
你都知道什么？
What do you know？
你不会是恰好有
You don't happen to be in possession
庞塞德莱昂的两只银杯吧？
of two silver chalices，circa Ponce de Leon？
没有
No.
我想也没有
Thought not.
为什么？
Why？
我听到一些说法
I hear stories.
谣传
Rumors.
你一定知道那个仪式
You are，of course，aware of the ritual.
对，我知道
Yes，I am.
是什么仪式？
What is it？
需要什么？
What is required？
一只人鱼，杰克
A mermaid，Jack.
你们搞错了
There's been a mistake.
是无期徒刑
It's a life sentence，
不是死刑
not death.
是无期！
Life！
巴船长
Barbossa.
各位，谢谢你们
Thank you，gentlemen.
我想你会绑绞绳吧
I trust you can tie a noose.
这是很困难的事
That's a hard thing，
逼一个人绑自己的绞绳
forcing a man to twis this own hanging rope.
你必须为你的行为付出代价
You must lie in your bed the way you made it.
你是怎么了？
What's happened to you？
杰克斯派罗呢？
Where be Jack Sparrow？
他逃走了
He escaped.
吉卜斯，我在赶时间
I'm on a tight schedule，Gibbs.
天佑号天一亮就启航
The HMS Providence sets sail at first light.
如果你不想尸体被吊在这里
If you do not care to watch it hanging here dead，
满嘴都是苍蝇...
with a mouth full of flies...
...现在就说
...speak now.
带上我吧
Take me with you.
去哪儿都行...
Any point of the compass...
吉卜斯，带你去哪呀？
Take you where，Gibbs？
不老泉？是吗？
The Fountain？Aye？
杰克也要去那儿吧？
Is that where Jack be headed？
吉卜斯，你能给我什么？
Have you anything you can offer me，Gibbs？
什么都没有？
Anything at all？
我说话算话
Upon me naked word，
你看不到日出了
you'll not see the dawn.
拿过来
Hand it over.
你这笨蛋！
You fool！
我正好有足够时间
I had just enough time
研究这些阴间的符号
to study those infernal circles.
每条路线，每个目的地
Every route，every destination.
全都在…这
All safe... in here.
吉卜斯先生，欢迎加入皇家海军
Welcome back to His Majesty's navy，Master Gibbs.
起床了，水手！
Show a leg，sailor！
是，长官
Aye，sir.
什么？
What？
这误会大了
There's been a horrible mistake.
继续走
Keep moving.
我不应该在这里
I'm not supposed to be here.
很多人在船上醒来
Many a man's woken up at sea，
都搞不清楚状况
no idea what，when，wherefore or why.
不记得前一晚
No memory of the night afore，
在哪签了什么合同
whence he signed up
还把钱通通拿去买醉
and drank away all his bonus money.
不，老兄，你不明白
No，no，no. You don't understand，mate.
我是杰克斯派罗船长
I'm Captain Jack Sparrow.
独此一家，如假包换
The original. The only.
我是石头，幸会了
Scrum，and the pleasure's all mine.
继续走
Now，keep moving.
石头
Scrum.
靠过来
Get your elbows in！
为什么那有一个玻璃棺？
Why is there a glass coffin？
看来像我管的？
Do I look like a man in charge？
我在哪里？
Where am I？
抱歉，斯派罗船长
'Scuse me，Captain Sparrow，sir.
我很荣幸欢迎你登上
I be right honoredto welcome you aboard
臭名狼藉的
our world-renowned vessel of infamy，
安妮王后复仇号
Queen Anne's Revenge.
黑胡子的船
Blackbeard.
干活
Work！
他是一个奇怪的家伙
He's a curious one.
他是活死人
He's been zombiefied.
啥？
活死人
Zombiefied.
黑胡子干的
Blackbeard's doing.
每个头儿都是
All the officers are the same.
好让他们更顺从
Makes 'em more compliant.
而且脾气一样坏
And perpetually ill-tempered.
快点，用力擦洗
Come on. Scrub.
是
Yeah.
拉！拉！用力拉！
Pull！Pull！Pull！
航行了五天，至少
Five days underway，at least.
对，你从海水味道闻出来的？
Aye. You can tell thatby the smell of the sea？
是船员的臭味
Smell of the crew.
喂，那可怜的混帐干了什么？
Oi. What did that poor sod do？
我该怎样才不会这样？
And how can I make sure to not？
他喔？是虔诚教徒
Him？Churchly fellow.
老念着万能的主啊
Always going on about the Lord Almighty.
宗教狂热份子在这艘船上？
Bible-thumper on this ship？
他以前是传教士
A missionary is his story.
我听说他是在一次劫掠中被抓来
What I heard was he got captured in a raid.
船上其他人全被杀了，除了他
Rest of the ship got killed，but not 'im.
大副不肯杀死他
First mate wouldn't let it happen
因为他信主
on account of his premier standing with the Lord.
大副以她的生命
A first mate sticking her neck
替囚犯求情
out for some prisoner.
那是你不能理解的
That you don't see.
“她”？大副是“女的”？
“Her”？First mate is a“her”？
回去干活！
Back to work！
稳稳地保持航向
Steady as she goes.
你是个无情的
You are a ruthless，
卑鄙的，超级难搞的坏蛋
soulless，cross-grained cur.
我跟你说过我有一艘船
I told you I had a ship.
不对，是黑胡子有一艘船
No，Blackbeard has a ship，
你害我变成囚犯
upon which I am now imprisoned.
杰克，我们办得到的
We can do this，Jack.
不老泉
The Fountain of Youth，
你不也一直想找到
like you always wanted.
黑胡子
Blackbeard.
爱德华汀奇
Edward Teach.
所有海盗都怕的海盗
The pirate all pirates fear.
有空就玩玩死人复活
Resurrector of the dead in his spare time.
他会听我的
He will listen to me.
他谁也不会听
He listens to no one.
也许会听他亲生女儿的？
Maybe to his own daughter？
女儿…亲生女儿？
Daughter as in... beget by？
失散很久
Long-lost.
最近才相认
Recently found.
全心全意爱她的老爸
Who loves her dear papa with all her soul.
他信这套鬼话？
He bought that？
我说服了他
I sold that.
那么找不老泉是为了他
Then it's the Fountain of Youth for him，
或者是为了你们
or him and you，
不是为了我们
not you and me.
不，杰克，最棒的是
No，Jack，that's the best part.
他就快要死了
He will be dead.
你要亲手杀了他？
You'll be handling that part yourself，then？
有一个预言
There is a prophecy.
也许你不相信超自然现象
Maybe you don't believein the supernatural.
喔，不
Oh，no，no.
这我倒是看过一两次
I've seen a thing or two.
这个预言是这样的：
The prophecy is this:
黑胡子两周内将会死亡
Blackbeard will meet his death within a fortnight
死在一个独腿者的手上
at the hands of a one-legged man.
所以他需要不老泉
That's why he needs the Fountain，Jack.
吉卜斯先生，我们没有地图
Master Gibbs，short we are a map.
也许你该好心
Perhaps you'd be so kindas
给我们一个航向
to provide us an heading.
麻烦倒杯酒给我
Be a gem and pour me a gulper.
不行，我们是私掠船
Nay. We be privateers，
不是海盗，吉卜斯先生
not pirates，Master Gibbs.
我们奉国王陛下之名行事
And in the king's name，we behave as such.
遵命，船长
Aye，Captain.
吉卜斯，我们是在正确的航线上吗？
Be we on the proper course，Gibbs？
对，是正确的
Aye，it be proper.
那就是证明
There's your proof.
西班牙舰队
The Spaniard.
全员注意，战斗位置
All hands！Battle stations！
航向上风
Get to windward！
全员注意，航向上风
All hands，windward！
加固两点
Harden up two points！
两点
Two points！
炮手解开大炮
Cast loose the cannons！
枪手，各就各位
Gunners，take posts！
就位，枪手待命，长官
Take position！Gunners ready，sir！
大炮解开，填弹
Out！Thrust！
等待命令
Await orders.
稳住
Steady！
填好炮弹，等待命令，长官
Guns armed，awaiting orders，sir.
长官，命令，长官？
Sir. Orders，sir？
他甚至都没有转动他的头
He never so much as turned his head.
不老泉才是目标
The Fountain is the prize.
看来他们不想浪费时间
It appears we be not even worth the time
击沉我们
it'd take to sink us.
我们已经落后了
And now we've fallen behind.
全员注意，全速前进
All hands，make more sail！
All hands，more sail！
让我们乘风破浪吧
Ride hard between wind and tide！
各位，我要说的可是叛变
The topic，gentlemen，is mutiny.
最可怕的叛变
Mutiny most foul.
是呀，我是来当杰克斯派罗的船员
Aye. I signed up to sail under Jack Sparrow，
不是冒牌船长
not some pretender.
而且还是个女的
And a lady，at that.
也没人提到船上有活死人
And mention was failed to be made of this uncanny crew.
我怕得腿都软了
Make my toes curl，they do.
我拿到了
I got 'em.
全部
All of them.
干得好
Well done.
好样的
Good lad.
我说，黑胡子
On to it，then. Blackbeard.
有什么习惯？
What are his habits？
他多半都待在船长室
Stays mostly to his cabin.
没错，都待在船长室
That's right，mostly to his cabin.
没错，但是当他出来...
Yes，but when he comes out...
他从来都不出来
He don't really come out.
他总是会出来吧
He must come out sometime.
并没有
Not really，no.
有人和他航海过？
Any of you sail with him before？
没，没有
No，no.
我从来没有
I've never.
绝对没有
Definitely not.
有人看过他？
Any of you seen him before？
并没有，没有
Not really，no.
他待在船长室
Stays to his cabin，
没人和他航海
no one sailed with him，
没人见过他...
no one's seen him...
各位，好消息
Good news，gentlemen.
这不是黑胡子的船
This is not Blackbeard's ship.
这不是安妮王后复仇号
This is not the Queen Anne's Revenge.
不对，这是安妮王后复仇号
No，this be the Queen Anne's Revenge，right enough.
你怎么知道？
How do you know？
我看过船名
I've seen the name，
就在船尾
on the back of the ship.
各位，各位伙伴...
Gentlemen，sirs，fellow conscriptees...
...你们都被骗了
...you have been monstrously deceived.
我们被耍了？
We are decepted，then？
没错
Yes.
你们都不知道目的地吧
You've nay been informed of a destination.
死亡就摆在我们面前了
Death lies before us
因为我们正航向
as we sail
不老泉
for the Fountain of Youth.
情况不妙啊，伙计们
It would be a sorry plight，mates.
我们死定了
Death，for certain.
那儿是幽灵的花园
The garden of darkened souls.
我们的葬生之地
Untimely our ends will be.
除非...
Unless...
...我们抢下这艘船
...we take the ship.
我们抢下这艘船，现在！
We take the ship，then. Now！
快去啊
Go on，then.
快帮忙，水手们！
Help me，shipmates！
给他们武器！
Give it to 'em！
起来！船是我们的！
Wake up！It's ours！
快一点！
Come on！
起来！让开！
Get up！Off your backside！
你们起来！
Get off your fannies！
给他们武器！
Take it to them，lads！
快帮忙！战斗！
Help me！Fight！
杰克
Jack.
如果这是梦
If this is a dream，
你可以留着剑和靴子
you can keep the sword and boots on.
如果不是...
If it's not...
这当然是梦
It's a dream.
不，才怪！
No，it's not！
我觉得该好心先给你警告
I thought I should give you fair warning，
我们要抢这艘船
we're taking the ship.
这不是个人恩怨
Nothing personal.
这对你可能比较好...
Think you might be better off if you just...
...你只要待着别插手
...stay out of it.
碍事
可恶！
Wretch！
是当伙伴还是当敌人！
You're either with us or against us！
我不支持你们
I am not with you，
也不反对你们！
neither am I against you！
他到底要怎么样？
Can he do that？
他本来就没有什么自己的立场
He's religious. I believe it's required.
奋战到底吧
Fight to the bitter end，
你们这群傻蛋！
you cack-handed deck apes！
抓住他
Take him，men.
把他绑牢了！
Tie him down tight！
船是我们的了！
The ship is ours！
各位
Gentlemen.
我被搞糊涂了
I be placed in a bewilderment.
我正在
There I were，
休息着
resting，
然后突然间
and upon a sudden，
听到甲板传来吵闹声
I hear an ungodly row on deck.
水手们擅离岗位
Sailors abandon their posts
没有命令，未经许可
without orders，without leave.
干粗活的水手
Men before the mast，
想要联手抢下这艘船
taking the ship for themselves.
那算什么呀，大副？
What be that，First Mate？
叛变，船长
Mutiny，Captain.
再说一次？
Again？
叛变！
Mutiny！
是啊
Aye.
叛变
Mutiny.
叛变者的下场是什么？
And what fate befalls mutineers？
大家都知道答案了，对吧？
Now，we know the answer to that，do we not？
你们这是自寻死路！
Mutineers hang！
船长，我要报告有人叛变
Captain，I wish to report a mutiny.
我能扳着指头数出来，一个个报给你听
I can name fingers and point names.
用不着，斯派罗先生
No need，Mr.Sparrow.
他们是喽啰
They are sheep.
你，才是主脑
You，their shepherd.
我有提过
Have I mentioned，sir，
你女儿有多美吗？
what a lovely daughter you have？
那她就是你死前最后的美景了
A fitting last sight for a doomed soul.
别忘了，父亲
Remember，Father.
我们需要他
We need him.
如果我不隔几天就杀个人
If I don't kill a man every now and then，
大家就会忘了我是谁
they forget who I am.
懦夫！
Coward！
他们不会忘记
They do not forget.
你的船员视你如恶棍
Your crew sees you for the miscreant you are.
是个懦夫，不管你杀多少人
A coward，no matter how many you slay.
我又被搞糊涂了
Twice in one day，I find myself in a bewilderment.
你没有被搞糊涂，你是害怕
You are not bewildered，you are afraid.
你不敢走向正义
You dare not walk the path of righteousness，
走向光明之路
the way of the light.
不对，我没那么复杂
No，sir. The truth is it be much simpler than all that.
我是个坏人
I am a bad man.
那，也是
That，too.
我也许也得杀了你，牧师
I might have to kill you too，catechist.
不行！
No！
就像她拉丁妈妈
All Latin blood like her mother.
父亲，求求你
Father，I beg you.
我又来了
There I be again，
老忘记传教士为什么在这里
forgetting why the missionary is here.
是我女儿想救赎我仅存的灵魂
My daughter fears for my soul，or what's left of it.
你真的想救赎我吗，我的孩子？
You truly wish to save me，my child？
每个灵魂都会被救赎
Every soul can be saved.
真的吗，年轻的牧师？
Be that true，young cleric？
是的
Yes.
我看虽然救赎你是有一点风险
Though you I sees a bit of a long shot.
我仍然为这地狱船上
Still，I pray for every unfortunate
每个不幸的灵魂祈祷
soulon this hell-bound vessel.
你用你的信仰解除了我的武装
You disarm me with your faith.
现在是八点！
Eight bells！
是哪个不幸的灵魂守了望台？
Which of you unfortunate soulsstood watch？
是我，是我在守望
I did. I stood watch.
炮手
Gunner.
是你？
You？
是
Aye.
好吧
厨子
The cook.
太好了，降下长艇！
Perfect. Lower the longboat！
掉头！
Bring her about！
你为什么要这样做？
Why do you do this？
叛变，我们的法律是清楚的
Mutiny. Our laws be clear.
我们的法律允许船长法外施恩
Our laws allow the Captain to show leniency.
我给过他机会决定他的命运
I have given this mana chance to determine his fate，
不是每个人都有的
a gift not afforded to all.
喔，现在你
Oh，you now.
有机会来显现你的祈祷的价值了
Chance to show the worth of your prayers.
祈祷他脱离…邪恶？
Pray he be delivered from... evil？
瞄准目标！
Course made！
住手，给他机会，也给你自己...
Stop. Give that man a chance. Give yourself a...
知道我在什么时候最接近造物主？
You know when I feel closest to our Maker？
在我看到苦难，痛苦和悲伤的时候
When I see suffering，pain and anguish.
这时祂才会显现真正的意图
That's when the true design of this world is revealed.
我看到是祂在苦难和悲剧发生时
And I see it revealed when in times of hardship and tragedy，
才对需要的人施予仁慈和怜悯
kindness and compassion are shown to those in need.
也许你该祈祷他不受伤害，是吧？
Perhaps you should pray for him to be unharmed，yes？
他还有机会...
Please，there's still hope...
再开炮！
Again！
其实我对不老泉毫无兴趣
I actually have no interest in the Fountain whatsoever，
如果你心意已定
so，if your heart is set，
那我就任你处置
you may drop me off anywhere you like.
舵手，可以了
That'll be all，Quartermaster.
你说的话像雾一样
Your words surround you like fog
让我看不透
and make you hard to see.
你呢，强大的黑胡子？
And what of you，the mighty Blackbeard？
听说你被砍头
Beheaded they say.
但你的身体还绕着你的船游三圈
Still，your body swam three times around your ship，
然后爬上船去
then climbed back onboard.
而现在你好好的
And here you are，
却怕得要命
running scared.
怕得要命
Scared.
要找不老泉
To the Fountain.
舵手有预知能力
The Quartermaster sees things before they happen.
他预知我的死亡
He has foreseen my death，
所以命运开口了
and so the fates have spoken.
我的命运已经决定
The threads of destiny woven.
你太高估命运的力量了
You have a ridiculously high regard for fate，mate.
那你呢？
And you？
我？
Me？
预知命运我是怀疑的...
I'm skeptical of predicting any future...
包括我自己
which includes me.
反抗命运是件傻事
It'd be foolish to battle fate，
但我想冒这个险
but I'd be tempted to cheat it.
我会找到不老泉
I will reach the Fountain.
你会带我去
You will lead me.
那把刀和你搞的
That knife will serve you no better than
叛变一样没用
the mutiny you devised.
叛变很有用
Mutiny served me well.
不是让我见到你了
It gained me an audience with you.
是啊
Aye.
我要警告你
To warn you.
注意你的大副
Regarding your first mate，
她并不是她说的那个人
who pretends to be persons she is not.
继续说
Do tell.
她不是你的女儿
She is not your daughter.
你胆敢这么说我的亲生骨肉？
You dare to speak thusly of my flesh and blood？
那女人是个高明的骗徒
Sir，the woman is consummate in the art of deception.
我很清楚
I know.
是我不小心
As I mostly unwittingly
让她走上这条路
set her on her wicked path.
虽然我不能说
Though I cannot claim credit for her
她的天赋是我教的
existing abundance of natural talent.
安洁莉卡，我钟爱的女儿
Angelica. My beloved daughter，
我这辈子做过最好的事
the one true good thing I have done in this life，
而你却自称你教坏了她？
and you claim to be the one who corrupted her？
她是纯粹的邪恶化身
Sir，what she is pure evil.
比野兽更令人害怕
More to be feared than a wild beast.
又饿又有尖牙的野兽
Hungry wild beast with gnashing teeth.
报复的，来自地狱的饥饿野兽...
Vengeful，hungry from hell beast...
父亲？
Father？
但是很可爱！
Sweetness！
不必伤害他的，父亲
No need to hurt him，Father.
他会帮助我们，对吧，杰克？
He will help us. Won't you，Jack？
瞧？到现在
You see？Even now，
她还是关心你的安危
she attends to your welfare，
虽然你一再说她是骗子
giving lie to the claims you make of her.
你会带我们到不老泉，对吧？
You will lead us to the Fountain. Yes？
换另一个方式说吧
Put another way.
要是我来不及赶到不老泉...
If I do not make it to the Fountain in time...
...你也去不了
...neither will you.
我马上仔细看
I'll have a wee look-see at those
这些航海图，好吧？
charts straight away then，shall I？
长官
Sir.
什么事？
Aye？
船长，长官
Captain，sir，
长官，我在船员中听到
I am unhappy to report rumors，sir，
关于目的地不好的谣言
among the crew，as to our destination.
闭上你的嘴给我离开
Shut your trap and make way.
你想抗命
That's the way of it，then.
无意冒犯，长官
No disrespect，sir.
他们怕什么？说出来
What do the men fear？Say it.
说出那个字
Speak the words.
白帽湾
Whitecap Bay.
是啊，白帽湾
Aye，Whitecap Bay.
所有没用的水手
And every worthless seaman fears the name，
都恐惧这名字
and rightly so，
虽然少数人知道原因或胆敢询问
though few know why or dare to ask.
传说是真的？
Be the stories true？
吉卜斯，说，是什么让你们动摇了
Say what robs you of your staunch heart，Gibbs，
否则永远留在幻想的领域
or forever leave it to the wider fields of fancy.
人鱼，船长
Mermaids，Captain.
是啊，人鱼
Aye. Mermaids.
大海食尸鬼，魔鬼鱼
Sea ghouls，devil fish，
令人恐惧的是超爱吃人肉
dreadful in hunger for flesh of man.
我们就是要经过人鱼海域
Mermaid waters，that be our path.
顾好你的灵魂，吉卜斯
Cling to your soul，Gibbs，
听说人鱼会把人吃到...
as mermaids be given to take the rest...
...只剩骨头
...to the bone.
冷静！冷静，大伙们！
Steady！Steady，men！
鼓起你们的勇气
Find your courage，
不然就准备恐惧吧！
or be ready to purpose your fear！
自求多福吧！
Save yourselves！
有人落水！
Man overboard！
不是！那是弃船者
Nay！A deserter.
改变航向
Come about.
不
Nay！
各位
Gentlemen，
我不会要求你们
I shall not ask any more of
做办不到的事
any man than what that man can deliver，
但我想问：我们是不是英国的臣民？
but I do ask this：Are we not king's men？
是
Aye.
那我们是不是国王的好臣民？
On the king's mission？
是
Aye.
当西班牙佬从旁经过时
I did not note any fear in the eyes
我在西班牙佬眼中看不到恐惧
of the Spanish as they passed us by.
你们敢不敢去白帽湾？
Are we not king's men？
敢！
Aye！
现在给我滚回自己的岗位干活！
Aye！Hands all off，and bear away！
直直航向白帽湾！
Stave on ahead to Whitecap Bay！
航向，白帽湾！
Bear on，Whitecap Bay！
来嘛
Come.
喝点酒？
Little drink？
美酒，音乐，烛光
Wine，music，candlelight.
这种事我们早就做过，杰克
I think we've traveled down this road before，Jack.
没错，我们是做过
Yes，we have.
我记得很清楚
I remember it well.
缠绕，扭曲和转动，回转，扭动着
Winding，twisting andturning，gyrating，writhing.
不停地扭动着
Incessant writhing.
记得圣多明哥吗？
Do you recall Saint Dominique？
拉马提尼克岛
La Martinique.
在圣多明哥我就想杀你了
I tried to kill you in Saint Dominique.
无所谓啦
Either or.
对一位大副几乎没有恰当的
Hardly appropriate for a first mate.
我是你的第一次吗？我总想知道
Was I the first？I've often wondered.
当你有欲望时真迷人，杰克
You can be so charming when you want something，Jack.
窍门是找出你想要什么
The trick is finding out what.
事实，是什么？
The truth，then，is it？
黑胡子已经达到他的目的
Blackbeard has served his purpose.
你和我一起去不老泉
You and I can go to the Fountain together，
一起沐浴在不老泉
where we shall bathe one another in equal shares of fame
尽情享受各种欢愉
and other assorted debaucheries.
而我告诉你不老泉的仪式
And I'll tell youthe ritual of the Fountain.
对，异教的仪式
Yes. The profane ritual.
我能信任你吗，杰克？
Can I trust you，Jack？
我需要你站在我这边
I need you on my side.
最亲爱的安洁莉卡
Oh，my dearest Angelica.
我们是神偷侠侣
You and I are asthick as thieves，love.
告诉我那个仪式
Tell me the rules.
不老泉的泉水
Water from the Fountain of Youth.
人鱼闪亮的泪水
The shimmering tear of a mermaid.
庞塞德莱昂的银杯
The silver chalices of Ponce de Leon.
只要用这些东西...
With these items...
怎样？
Yes？
用这些东西
With these items，
你就能得到另一个人的全部岁月
you may take all the years of life from another，Jack.
杰克，你知道这意味着什么
You know what that means.
我们俩不能单独去
We cannot go alone，you and I.
仪式需要一名牺牲者
The ritual requires a victim.
这真不幸
That is unfortunate.
是啊
Yes，it is.
我对不老泉的欲望都没了
I find my desire for the Fountaing reatly lessened.
不过船上有你想要的东西
But there is something on board you do want.
黑胡子来了怎么办？
What about Blackbeard？
他在海图室
He's in the chart room.
我们要快点
We'll have to be quick.
他把每艘船当成战利品保存着
He keeps each ship as a prize.
只要你帮我
You help me，
我保证让你挑你要的船
and I promise you your pick.
虽然我知道你会挑哪一艘
Though I think I know the one you will choose.
黑珍珠号在瓶子里？
The Black Pearl in a bottle？
黑珍珠号怎么会在瓶子里？
Why is the Black Pearl in a bottle？
那只猴子缩小了还是那么讨厌
He's even more annoying in miniature.
我们就这么说定了咯，杰克？
Do we have a deal，Jack？
安洁莉卡，我了解你
Angelica，I know you.
你不会偷走无辜者的生命
You are not going to steal the life of some innocent man.
独腿者的怎么样？
What about the one-legged man？
杰克，我需要岁月
I need years，Jack.
不是为我
Not for me.
是为了我的父亲
For my father.
我真的是黑胡子的女儿
I am truly the daughter of Blackbeard.
你迷失在自己的假话了
You've fallen for your own con，love.
不是的，他是我的父亲
No，he is my father.
我对你说的假话不全是假的
The lies I told you were not lies.
你对我说的假话都是真的？
You lied to me by telling me the truth？
对
Yes.
这招厉害
That's very good.
我能用这招吗？
May I use that？
少来，我肯定你会的
I'm sure you will，anyway.
我当然会罗
Of course I will.
所以，你不会放弃这个搜寻？
So，will you not give up this quest？
我想要父爱，杰克
I want a father，Jack.
我不曾有过
I haven't had one.
安洁莉卡，你的父亲，黑胡子...
Angelica，your father，Blackbeard...
...他很邪恶
...he is evil，
而且有机会他会杀了你
and he will kill you given the chance.
他是无法被救赎的
He cannot be saved.
你又凭什么来规定救赎界限？
And who are you to set the limits on redemption？
你偷走了我的青春
You stole years of my life，Jack.
这是你欠我的
You owe me.
你这是在自己找死
And you are en route to getting yourself killed，
我不想袖手旁观
and I am not inclined to stand by and watch.
白帽湾到了！
Whitecap Bay！
全员集合！
All hands on deck！
准备上长艇！
Set to the longboats！
把渔网摆平！
Lay 'em out flat！
不要打结
No tangles.
弄漂亮点迎接我们美丽的娇客
Make 'em look pretty for our dainty guests.
我们需要灯光
We're gonna need light.
很强的灯光
A lot of light.
跟我来！
Come！
闻到了吗？鲸鱼油，
Smell that？Whale oil.
燃烧的火光像是上帝的奇蹟
Stuff burns like a miracle from God.
你能点燃灯塔吗？
Can you make it work？
英国佬制造的
Made by the English.
我们就不要期望太大了
Let's not get our hopes up.
月亮新的周期
The old moon in the arms of the new one.
夏季第一次开始时
First of the summer.
最适合搜集人鱼的泪水
Perfect for hunting a mermaid's tear.
我们完蛋了
We're doomed.
她们会被人工灯光吸引
They be drawn to man-made light.
鲨鱼？
Sharks？
比鲨鱼更可怕，小子
Worse than sharks，boy.
一小时后人鱼就会来袭
There'll be mermaids upon us within the hour，
你们记住我的话
you mark my words.
我们就是诱饵
And we're the bait.
我听说从人鱼那得到亲吻
I heard it said a kiss from a mermaid
就可以保证水手不会淹死
protects a sailor from drowning.
别傻了！
Don't be a fool！
孩子，人鱼都是女的
Mermaids are all female，son，
而且个个美如天仙
and lovely as a dream of heaven.
到了搅拌奶油的时间
But when it comes time to churn butter，so to speak，
她们就从长艇
they snatch a sailor out of a boat
或甲板上抓走一个水手
or off the deck of a ship，have their way，
然后这些水手被拉到海底
and then the sailors are pulled to bottom
被淹死然后被吃掉
and drowned and eaten.
要不然，有时，是另一种结局
Or，sometimes，the other way around.
唱歌
Sing.
什么？
What？
她们喜欢听人唱歌
They like to hear singing.
我的名字是玛丽亚
My name is Maria
一个商人的女儿
A merchant's daughter fair
大声点
Louder.
我离开我的双亲
And I have left my parents
放弃3千英镑年薪
And 3,000 pounds a year
我的心被爱神一箭射中
My heart is pierced by Cupid
黄金在我眼中变成粪土
I disdain all glittering gold
从此没有什么能安慰我
There is nothing can console me
除了那个快乐勇敢的水手
But my jolly sailor bold
我的心被爱神一箭射中
My heart is pierced by Cupid
黄金在我眼中变成粪土
I disdain all glittering gold
从此没有什么能安慰我
There is nothing can console me
除了那个快乐勇敢的水手
But my jolly sailor bold
主救救我
Lord save me.
你们看，看那里
Man，look. Look there.
不要这样，你会吓走她！
You'll scare her off！
好啊，能吓走最好！
Aye，and good riddance！
你会说话吗？
Can you talk？
会
Yes.
你很美丽
You're beautiful.
那个唱歌的人是你？
Are you the one who sings？
对
Aye.
你是我那个快乐的水手？
Are you my jolly sailor bold？
是的，我是
Aye，that I be.
石头，控制你自己！
Scrum，comport yourself！
我短短悲惨的生活
Boys！There ain't much been given to me
没人给我什么
in my brief，miserable life，there's the truth in it.
但我现在可以骄傲地说
But，by God，I'll have it said
一个美人鱼给了我一个吻！
that Scrum had himself a kissfrom a proper mermaid！
我的心被爱神一箭射中
My heart is pierced by Cupid
黄金在我眼中变成粪土
I disdain all glittering gold
从此没有什么能安慰我
There is nothing can console me
除了那个快乐勇敢的水手
But my jolly sailor bold
来吧美丽的姑娘们
Come all ye pretty fair maids
无论你是谁
Whoever you may be
深爱着快乐勇敢的水手
Who love a jolly sailor bold
在怒海中乘风破浪而行
That ploughs the raging sea
我的心被爱神一箭射中
My heart is pierced by Cupid
黄金在我眼中变成粪土
I disdain all glittering gold
从此没有什么能安慰我
There is nothing can console me
除了那个快乐勇敢的水手
But my jolly sailor bold
我的心被爱神一箭射中
My heart is pierced by Cupid
黄金在我眼中变成粪土
I disdain all glittering gold
从此没有什么能安慰我
There is nothing can console me
除了那个快乐勇敢的水手
But my jolly sailor bold
她们现身了！人鱼开始了！
Out upon it！It has begun！
照着她们！
Light 'em up！
鼓起你们的勇气！
Muster your courage！
把她们逼到岸边！
Drive 'em to shore！
赶快撒网！快点！
Nets into the water！Quickly！
撤退，所有人，上岸！保住你们的命！
Retreat，all，to land！For your lives！
我说，撤退！
Retreat，I say！
懦夫！回到海里！
Cowards！Back in the water！
上岸也无法活命！我保证！
There be no refuge on land！On my word！
快呀！
Come on！
逮到一只了！
We got one！
我坠入爱河了！
I'm in love！
检查伤者！
Check the wounded！
看看能不能找到一只活着的人鱼！
See if you can find one mermaid still alive！
快点，快帮忙！
Come，give a hand！
干得好，水手
Well done，sailor.
大家伙儿都见着没？
Did everyone see that？
别让我再来一次了哈
Because I will not be doing it again.
回船上去
Back to the ship.
我们去安全港湾
We head for a protected cove.
现在就去
Now.
天啊，那是什么？
Lord. Is that？
人鱼
Mermaid.
马上放弃这疯狂任务吧
Give up this madness now.
办不到
I cannot.
我们不但要踏着两条脚印去
Ever walk on the beach，
还要踏着两条脚印回来
look back and see your footsteps in the sand？
就像这样，只不过脚印在我的面前
It's like that，except the footsteps lie before me.
你去的时候都不是两条脚印
Footstep，actually.
长官，这里是白帽湾
Whitecap Bay，sir.
我们得快点走
We must hasten.
我们要用走的
We travel by foot.
吉卜斯，给我一个方向
Gibbs，I require a heading.
长官，但是，那些水手
But，sir，the men.
他们早就死了
They be dead already.
他们听起来还没死
They don't sound dead.
喔，是吗？
Oh，is that so？
我只听到海鸥归巢的声音
Well，I hear nothing but seagulls nesting.
葛先生，你又听到什么了？
What is it that you hear，Mr. Groves？
海鸥…归巢
Seagulls... nesting.
没别的声音了
Nothing more.
吉卜斯，方向？
Heading，Gibbs？
我的天
My God.
你的脑袋或是我的方向
Your head or my heading.
快选择
I'll have me one or t'other，
我才不管你死活
I don't care which.
全体船员，前进！
All hands，forward！
斯派罗，该你上场了
It's to you now，Sparrow.
真的有必要吗？
Was that really necessary？
你最好不知道我的船在哪
Best you not know the exact wherea bouts of my ship.
我这人很小心
I be a cautious man.
我也一样
So be I.
我最想要的是...
What I want first...
...是庞塞德莱昂的船
...is Ponce de Leon's ship.
干嘛带着她？
Why is it we've got to bring her along？
泪水会干掉
Because tears don't keep.
我们需要新鲜的人鱼泪水
We need them fresh.
到底是什么鬼仪式？
What is the ritual again？
需要不老泉泉水和人鱼泪水？
Water from the Fountain and a mermaid's tear？
还有两只银杯
And two silver chalices.
一杯有一滴泪水，另一杯没有
One cup with a tear，one without.
一杯有一滴泪水而两杯都有泉水？
So，one with a tear and water in both？
很复杂的，不是吗？
Quite complicated，is it not？
两杯都有泉水
Both get water.
一杯有一滴泪水
One gets a tear.
喝下掺了泪水的那个人
The person who drinks the water with the tear
将得到另一个人的一生岁月
gets all the years of life from the other.
到底是多少岁月？
How many years？
他过去的岁月
All the years that they have lived，
以及以后的岁月
and they could have lived，
如果命运对他够好的话
if fate had been kinder.
牧师
Clergyman.
如果我有什么不测
On the off chance that this does not go well for me，
我愿意接受
I would like it noted here and now
任何宗教信仰
that I am fully prepared to believe in whatever I must，
只要死了以后可以去那个
so that I may be welcomed into that place
好人都能去的地方？
where all the goody-goodies get to go. Savvy？
杰克，有一个方法
We have a word for that，Jack.
你可以改变信仰
You can convert.
不过我是在有需要的时候
I was thinking more of an as-needed basis.
舵手！
Quartermaster！
什么事？
Aye？
她不能呼吸了！
She cannot breathe！
她有水
She has water.
她需要空气！
She needs air！
把这个打开来
Open this.
她会逃走
She will escape.
你会害死她
You're killing her.
我支持传教士
I support the missionary's position.
瞧？
See？
继续前进
Onward.
我就知道
Just as I thought.
不是这个方向！
Not this way！
就是这个方向，没错？
This is the way，isn't it？
当然是，但我们应该从东边绕过去
'Course it is，but we should go around to the east.
那会偏离圣盃之路
That would take us out of the path of the chalices.
我们会绕回去
Well，then we'll circle back.
没时间了
There is no time.
是你非要带上这条该死的人鱼
You're the one who insisted on bringing the bloody mermaid.
你搞叛变也浪费不少时间
Well，the mutiny didn't help.
你走路很娘
You walk like a girl.
你走路才娘
You would know.
总要有人自愿
Someone must go.
你是说兵分两路？
You mean split up？
你是说跳崖？我等不及要看
You mean jump？This I cannot wait to see.
斯派罗自愿跳崖
Sparrow will go.
找到船，取回圣盃
Find the ship，retrieve the chalices.
斯派罗？你怎么知道他会回来？
Sparrow？What makes you think he will come back？
对啊，你怎么知道他会回来？
Yes，what makes you think he will come back？
父亲，不能相信他，我去
We cannot trust him，Father. I'll go.
她自愿去
She'll go.
不老泉还有多远？
How much farther to the Fountain？
我快没有时间了
I'm running out of time.
沿着这条河，向北走一天
About a day's march north，following that river，
会到达一连串的池塘
you'll get to a series of pools.
就很接近了
Then you're close.
你要跳下去
You will go.
我就知道会这样
I was sure it would come to this.
都说人从上面
You know that feeling you get sometimes
往下看的时候？
when you're standing in a high place？
会有跳下去的冲动？
Sudden urge to jump？
但我没有
I don't have it.
我需要那两只圣盃
I need those chalices.
毙了我吧
Shoot.
我不想摔死
Save me the bother of the fall.
你要跳下去，然后回来...
You will go. You will return...
...不然我就杀了她
...or I will kill her.
你不会杀死自己的女儿
You won't kill your own daughter.
舵手，给我六把手枪
Quartermaster，get me six more pistols，
两把装上子弹
remove the shot from all but two，
但别告诉我是那两把
but do not tell me which two.
斯派罗先生，你来选
You get to choose，Mr. Sparrow.
不
No.
就这把
Yes.
你确定？
You're sure？
当然了
'Course I am.
再挑一把
Again.
拜托，根本没装子弹
Please，they're not even loaded.
再挑一把
Again.
你这么想杀她
If you're so keen on killing her，
为什么不让她跳？
why don't you just let her jump？
什么？
What？
如果你摔死
If you jump and die，
那就轮到她
then she will have her chance.
再挑一把
Again.
喂...
Oi...
...从上面跳下去
...if I jump，
我能活命吗？
will I survive？
娃娃
The doll.
现在你能活命了
Yes，now you will survive.
胡说八道！我来跳
This is nonsense！I'm going！
湿了，我又湿了！
Wet. Wet again.
我们继续
We go on.
往北走向不老泉
Due north to the Fountain.
父亲，干得好
Well played，Father.
你早知道哪把枪有子弹，对吧？
You knew which guns were loaded，right？
乖女儿，当然了
Of course，my love.
要是有地图就好了
Be nice to have a map about now.
或是一艘船
Or a ship.
站住！千万别动
Stop！Hold very still.
别让它碰到你的皮肤
Ye dare not let it touch your skin.
怎么？有个嗜好有什么不对？
What？What be wrong with an older man having a hobby？
你停下来干嘛，嗯？快走！
What are you stopping for，eh？Push on！
快走！
Push on！
等你们死了有的是时间睡
You can sleep when you're dead.
快走！
Push on！
不老泉眷顾我们
Fortune continues to favor us.
圣地牙哥号
The Santiago.
著名的庞塞德莱昂指挥舰
Famously captained by Ponce de Leon.
那里没有人
There's no one there.
对的
Right，then.
我们不能停下来
We must not stop.
你得走路
You will walk.
我不会走路
I cannot.
不走就死
Walk or die.
我来扶你
Put your arms around me.
我没要求帮助
I do not ask for help.
但你需要帮助
But you need it.
我们在赶时间，对吧？
We're in a hurry，yes？
不要落后了
Do not fall behind.
在这暂停一下！
Hold here 'til I say！
你真美丽
Such beauty.
你一定是上帝亲手制作的
Surely you're one of God's own creations，
并不是没上方舟的
and not a descendant of those dark creatures
那些落难者的后代
who found no refuge on the Ark.
你真美丽...
Such beauty...
...但是致命
...and yet deadly.
致命？不是的
Deadly？No.
你攻击我
You attacked me.
不是这样的
No.
你和他们不一样
You are different.
不一样？
Different？
不是吗？
Are you not？
你保护了我
You protect.
是你做的？
Did you？
是你把我从爆炸中救出来
You pushed me down out of the way.
你看到不老泉吗？
You see the Fountain？
没有，但是我们很接近了
No，but we are close.
把那怪物带来
Bring the creature.
罩住它的头
Cover its head.
她有名字！
She has a name！
请赐教
Pray tell.
她是莎琳娜
She is Syrena.
庞塞德莱昂
Ponce de Leon.
40个海盗做上40个晚上发财梦
If 40 pirates dreamt 40 nights of treasure，
也梦不到这么多的金银财宝
it would not match the contents of this room.
你
You.
不...
No...
...你
...you.
我先来的
I was here first.
你，为什么会在这里？
You，why are you here？
黑胡子派我来的
Blackbeard sent me.
你又是为什么咧？
Why are you？
银杯
Silver chalices
替我的国王取回
for my royal liege.
噢，拜托
Oh，please.
退后，退后！我们得保持平衡！
Back，back！We have to balance it out！
整艘船会滑下去！
The whole ship will slide！
对喔
Right，then.
如果我们各挑一个
What if we each choose an item
差不多重的东西？
of approximately equal weight？
放回去！
Put it back！
我们什么都别碰！
We touch nothing！
那个呢？
What about that？
圣盃
The chalices.
喂！你凭什么可以先看？
Oi！Why do you get to look first？
好吧
Fine，then.
我们一起看
Together.
是石头
Rocks.
西班牙佬
The Spanish.
他们赶在我们前面
They're ahead of us，mate.
我要看看那张地图
I shall have a look at that map.
一定有鬼...
If it's what I fear...
不然他们干嘛把地图留下来
I wonder why they left this behind.
别动那张地图
Don't touch the map.
他们知道路线
They know the path，
但我知道
but I can also see where
他们会在哪儿紮营
they'll most likely make camp.
杰克！
Jack！
吉卜斯，我正准备策划去监狱救你
Gibbs，I was just on me way to break you out of jail.
你偷走了我的地图
You stole my map.
够了，该走了
Right. Best be started.
遵命？
Ol？
人鱼
Mermaids.
注意，这些池塘很深
Careful，these pools run deep.
要是她逃走，一切就完了
If she escapes，all is lost.
舵手
Quartermaster.
看，快看！
Look. Look！
她被钉住
Staked out to die，
被太阳晒死
to dry in the sun.
身体只有一半在水里
Only half in the water.
虽然活不了
Not enough to live，
但是却能让她慢慢折磨而死
but just enough to make the dying slow.
想想看
Think on it.
你的族人，被杀死
Your people，murdered，
她们的泪水被收集
harvested for their tears.
莎琳娜，你怎么不哭？
Syrena，won't you cry？
你们全都快死了，你也是
All die，even you.
我听得见，很快
Soon，I hear.
听好...
Listen...
听好
Listen.
听得见你的姊妹们在尖叫吗？
Can you not hear your sisters scream？
你听不见是吗？
Do you not hear them？
我们只需要一滴泪水
We need but one tear.
低等的生物！
Vile creature！
切断她的手指，一根一根！
Chop off her fingers，one by one！
窒息她！
Choke her！
挖出她的眼睛采集泪水！
Cut out the tears from behind the eyes！
你怎么不说话？
Where's your voice in this？
日出后
Maybe she'll have a change of heart
她也许会改变主意
when the sun rises.
对，她会被晒死
Oh，aye，she will burn，
但我等不及了
but I cannot wait for the sun.
也许我们该升火
Perhaps we should build a fire.
不
No.
牧师，别想违抗我
Do not contest me，cleric.
你不能折磨她
You will not torture her.
我们只需要一滴泪水
We need only one tear.
我会把她身上的鳞片刮下来
I will tear every scale from her body one by one if I see fit.
如果你不高兴，就滚回去祷告吧
If that displeases you，go pray.
我错了
I was wrong.
不是每个灵魂都能救赎
Not every soul can be saved.
你的就不能
Yours cannot.
看哪，各位
Behold，gentlemen，
信仰就是这么不可靠
a man formerly of faith.
你口中的低等生物
That vile creature，as you call her，
远胜你百倍
is worth a hundred of you.
喔，你关心她？
Oh，you care for her？
你喜欢她
You fancy her.
别否认，我全都看在眼里
And do not deny what is clear to my eyes.
问题是...
Question is...
...她喜不喜欢你？
...does she fancy you？
天啊，她喜欢你
By God，she does.
咱们走运了
We are in luck！
流一滴泪水...
Bring forth a tear...
...或是亲眼看着他死
...or witness the death of this poor soul.
莎琳娜，要是你能挤出一滴泪
Syrena，if you could manage a tear，
我就感激不尽
I would be grateful.
她可怜你
Sadness，yes，
但并不悲伤...还没有
but no sorrow... yet.
父亲！你不能杀他
Not by your hand，Father！
时间不会等待任何人，舵手
Time and tide wait for none.Quartermaster.
好哇，人鱼真的很顽固
Aye，mermaids are tough.
这些怪物
The lot of them.
把她跟其他人鱼一样绑起来
Tie her up like the others.
把他的尸体丢掉
And get rid of this.
你有信心？
You are confident？
当然
Yes.
我是女人，她也是
I am a woman. So is she.
杰克，你玩什么把戏？
What's your play，Jack？
居然和巴船长合作
Throwing in with Barbossa.
有一个女生...
There is a girl...
...一个女人
...a female
...我们的异性
...of the opposite sex.
你几时没有过女人？
When is there not？
或许我应该说“小妞”
Perhaps I should say“damsel. ”
你要营救一个小妞？
You're rescuing a damsel？
好啊，这倒新鲜
Well，there's a first.
对，不过就是很久以前
Yes，but it's just that I may have caused said damsel
我可能对这位小妞造成伤害了
some manner of harm many moons ago.
说实话吧
Out with it.
吉卜斯，这女人来自塞维利亚
Gibbs，this is the woman from Seville.
啊，你假装爱她
Ah，you pretended to love her，
然后伤了她的心
then you left her and broke her heart.
更糟
Worse.
我可能有过，一下下，怎么说...
I may have had，briefly，mind you...
...心动
...stirrings.
心动？
Stirrings？
心动
Stirrings.
你说什么？
What？
你是说，动真情了？
Like feelings，you mean？
不
No，no，no.
不算是真情
Not quite all the way to feelings.
更像是...
More like...
好啦，是真情，败给你了
All right，feelings，damn you.
但你还是抛弃了她
And you left her still.
你真卑鄙
That's low.
谢谢夸奖
Thank you.
最好不要硬来
Stealth over force.
考虑你的状况，接下来让我来吧
I'll take it from here on account of your condition.
你的假腿没被白蚁蛀掉吧？
You don't have termites，do you？
杰克，谢谢你的关心
I appreciate your concern，Jack，
但我还是要跟你一起去
but I'll be keeping you company all the same.
少校，留在这里
Hold here，Lieutenant Commander.
等我的信号
Wait for my signal.
在那里，那一个
There. That one.
他一定是首领
That be the leader.
记住他的帐篷，因为那里...
Make note of his tent because that's where...
不，等等
No，wait.
老天，银杯就在那里
By God，that must be them right there.
你的剑有股怪味
Your sword smells funny.
那是毒蟾蜍的毒液
Aye. Poison from the innards of poisonous toads.
只要被刮伤
Just a scratch，
马上没命
you're a dead man in minutes.
你能不能把剑指向别的方向？
Would you mind pointing it the other way？
我不喜欢蟾蜍
I don't like toads.
你在干嘛？
What are you doing？
安排脱逃路线啊
Planning an escape route.
你不都是这样做的？
Isn't that how you do it？
是啊
Yes.
但有时候我会...
Or sometimes I just...
随机应变
improvise.
现在要做什么？
Now what？
我们慢慢走出去
We stroll out，slow and steady.
别当自己是外人
Just like we belong.
莎琳娜，对不起
I'm sorry，Syrena.
菲利普，你还活着
Philip，you're alive.
对
Yes.
你回来救我
You came for me.
为什么？
Why？
你很不同，不是吗？
You're different，are you not？
你不是很善良？有同情心？
Do you know not of kindness？Compassion？
为什么人鱼
Tears of sorrow，never.
悲伤痛苦没有泪水
Mermaids be too tough for that.
快乐感动才会有...
But tears of joy...
听说这种泪水更有效
They say these be the more potent anyway.
莎琳娜，我发誓
Syrena，on my word，
这与我无关
I had no part in this.
放了她，你不需要她了
Let her go. You don't need her now.
放了她？不行
Let her go？No.
把她绑紧
Secure her bonds.
让她自生自灭
We leave her with her own.
你的逃跑路线呢？
How's that escape route working？
现在只能靠你随机应变啦
Here's your chance to improvise.
我也想呀
I'm attempting it.
只要弄松一只手就行
I might be able to get a hand loose.
喔，你藏了刀子，太好了
Oh，you got a knife. That's very good.
比那更好
Better.
我也要一支
I want one of those.
敬复仇
Here's to revenge.
甜蜜的复仇
Sweet and clear.
什么复仇？
Revenge？
老巴，行了，别装了
Come，come，Hector.
如果你想要圣盃
If you wanted the chalices，
你就会看出它们不见了
you'd seen they were missing and gone.
你趴在那，等着偷袭黑胡子
You were lying in wait，for Blackbeard.
乔治王，私掠船，假发
King George. Privateer. Wig.
全都是装出来的
Cheap theatrical facade.
我才不信
I'm not buying it.
那天晚上你又不在场
You weren't there that night.
失去黑珍珠号的那晚
When the Pearl was lost？
是被抢走，不是失去
Taken，not lost.
我们在伊斯帕尼奥拉海岸被突击
We were off the coast of Hispaniola when we came under attack.
完全没有预警也没得交涉
No provocation nor warning nor offer of parley.
我们被炮火猛烈攻击
We were peppered with cannon fire.
然后在黑珍珠号下的海水开始搅动
And then the sea beneath the Pearl began to roil.
黑珍珠号剧烈地摇晃
The Pearl was pitching and yawing violently.
每个跳板，每个栏杆
Every plank，every rail，
每个帆柱，一下子，开始吱吱作响
every spar，all at once，began to creak.
船上的缆绳就像有生命一样
The rigging had come to life.
我们自己的船居然跟我们做对...
Our own ship turned against us...
...绑着船员，像蛇一样绑着他们
...tangling the crew，wrapping around 'em like snakes.
还缠上了我的腿
And wrapping around me leg.
但我双手是自由的而且手里还握着剑
But me arms were free and me sword was to hand.
我的船由我主宰，不是黑胡子
I am the master of me ship，not Blackbeard.
我的生命由我主宰，不是黑胡子
I am the master of my fate，not Blackbeard.
所以我做了我该做的事
So I did what needed done.
我活下来了
I survived.
...你不是来找不老泉的
So... you're not after the Fountain.
我才不管乔治王或那些
I care not for King George or tavern yarns
可以治愈腿伤的无稽之说
that give hope for a healed limb.
我甚至愿意牺牲左手
But I'd give my left arm
换取杀黑胡子的机会
for a chance at Blackbeard.
不是右手？
Not your right？
我需要好用的右手
I need me good arm
把毒剑刺进他的心脏
to drive my poisoned blade through his heart.
老兄，你会有机会的
I'll see you get the chance，mate.
俘虏逃走了
The prisoner's escaping.
他逃走了！散开！找到他！
He's escaping！Fan out！Find him！
走！快走！
Go！Go！
别开枪！我要抓活的！
Hold your fire！I want him alive！
我觉得那就是信号了
I figured that was the signal.
快走！准备出发！
Go！Prepare to move out！
敌人很快就会找到我们
The enemy is soon upon us.
杰克，抱歉没拿到圣盃
I'm sorry about the chalices，Jack，
但我在赶时间
but I've an appointment to keep.
我不会回去拿的
I'll not be going back.
没必要
No need.
要不要来一杯？
Shall we have a drink？
我们去不老泉喝
We'll drink at the Fountain.
为什么每次见面
How is it we can never meet without
你都拿着东西指着我？
you pointing something at me？
斯派罗，你把圣盃带来了？
You brought the chalices，Sparrow？
是的，喂！
Aye. Oi！
你还带了个朋友
I see you brought a friend.
是的
I did.
独腿者，在附近？
And the one-legged man，he is near. Aye？
是的
Aye.
好了...
Now...
在我把它们拿给你之前
Before I go just handing them over，
你必须答应我两个条件
I do have one or two conditions.
说
Name them.
第一个
Firstly，
把罗盘还给我
I'll be having me compass back.
不，那是第二个
No，no，that's secondly.
第一个，你发誓
Firstly，upon your word，
不伤害安洁莉卡
you will bring no harm to Angelica.
斯派罗，我不会向你这种人发誓
I'll make no vows to the likes of you，Sparrow.
不过答应你不伤害她
But it costs me nothing to admit
对我没有损失
that she was never in harm's way.
第二个，比第一个重要
Secondly then，priorly firstly，
把罗盘还给我
I will be having me compass back.
拜托啦？那是我应得的
Please？I do deserve it.
你知道那臭猪
Do you have any idea how difficult
有多难绑吗？
it was to catch that filthy pig？
不是两条腿的
Not the big one，
是那四条腿的
the four-legged one.
谢谢你
Thank you.
第三个
And thirdly，
黑胡子先生
Mr. Beard，
有时候呀，不是常常
there are times，not very often，
在反省我的滔天罪行时
when I do reflect upon my heinous misdeeds.
最恶劣的
Chief among them，
是我对待吉卜斯先生的态度
I note how poorly I have treated Mr. Gibbs，
我忠心耿耿的大副
my loyal first mate.
对啊！现在你才想到...
Aye！Now you bring it up...
留下他在监狱里腐烂
Left him to rot in jail，I did.
我不在乎
Didn't care.
现在还是不在乎
Still don't.
但，这次
But，point being，
你必须放过他
you must let him go free.
就这些？
Is that it？
我想是的
I think so.
快决定，猪要是跑了
Quick，or the pig runs，
祝好运找到圣盃
and good luck getting those chalices.
杰克，如果我是你，我一定...
Jack，if it's all the same to you，I'd be just as...
同意
Done.
放了那头猪
Release the swine.
如果，你们不介意
Perhaps，if you don't mind，
我想跟着去...
I could tag along with you folk for a...
老兄，这会指引你奔向自由
This will lead you to freedom，mate.
我发誓
I could have swore
不老泉就在这附近
it was somewhere right around here.
我们不能停下
We must not stop.
死路
Dead end.
Dead. End.
死路
Dead end.
杰克，我觉得
Jack，I'm starting to think
你不知道地点
you don't know where you're going.
俗话说，重要的是旅程不是结果
It is not the destination so much as the journey，they say.
圣盃，拜托
Chalices，if you please.
后退
Stand back.
杰克...
Jack...
...你有没有，真的...
...have you ever，in fact...
...亲眼见到
...seen with your own eyes
...不老泉？
...the Fountain of Youth？
抱歉，请重复你的问题？
I'm sorry，could you repeat the question，please？
舵手
Quartermaster.
不！
No，no！
等等！
Wait，wait！Wait.
“生命...之水”
“Aqua...de Vida.”
石头先生...
Master Scrum...
...可不可以？
...do you mind？
阁下？
Squire？
真漂亮
So beautiful.
斯派罗，我是第一个喝的
Sparrow，I'll be the first to taste those waters.
父亲
Father.
独腿人
The one-legged man.
你把他带来这里
You brought him here.
我会这么做？
Would I do that？
爱德华汀奇！
Edward Teach！
对于你在公海上犯下的罪行
For crimes committed on the high seas，
奉国王陛下之名授予我的权力...
by the authority granted me by His Majesty the King...
...以及个人满意的优厚条件...
...and with a goodly amount of personal satisfaction...
...依法逮捕你
...I hereby place you in the custody of the court，
你现在是我的犯人了
and declare you to be my prisoner.
我的路到尽头了，是这么说吧？
My trick's out，is that it？
你犯的罪行包括有，海盗罪，叛国罪
Such crimes do include，but are not limited to，piracy，treason，
谋杀罪，最可恶的酷刑罪
murder，torture of the most heinous sort，
还有残忍剥夺别人右腿罪
including the brutal theft of one used，twisted，hairy right leg.
你...敢不敢面对这把剑？
You... dare face this sword？
离你的船这么远？当然敢
This far away from your ship？Aye.
我感到命运冷酷的气息在我颈后
Aye. That be the cold breath of fate I feel down my nape.
以上帝之名，我会和你决一死斗
But I'll have one last fight，by God.
杀了他们！
Kill 'em all！
等一下
Hang on a minute.
我只是...
I just...
我只是想搞清楚一些事
I just need to understand something.
来到这里
Right，so，
你们要打他们
you will fight against them，
他们要打你们
they will fight against you.
就因为他的腿被他砍了？
All on account of him wanting to kill him？
这什么逻辑？
Where is the sense？
我没说错吧
Exactly.
这样吧，让他们单挑
I say，let them fight each other，
我们别插手，边看，边喝酒
while we lay back，watch，have a drink，
顺便赌赌输赢！
place some wagers！
好
Aye.
杀了他们！
Kill 'em！
不留余地！
No quarter！
滚开！
Get off me！
石头，圣盃！
Scrum，the chalices！
还有人鱼泪水！跟我来！
And the tear！Follow！
杀呀！
Fight！
拿过来
Hand it over.
人鱼泪水，这才是好样的
The tear. There's a good lad.
比起怕你，我更怕她
I'm more afraid of her than I am of you.
拿过来，这才是好样的
Hand it over. There's a good lad.
圣盃，拜托
The chalices，if you please.
杰克，抱歉
Sorry，Jack.
我跟你说过，我需要岁月
I told you，I need years.
现在，你的就行了
And now，yours will do.
石头！
Scrum！
莎琳娜...
Syrena...
主啊，你不能带她走
Oh God，you will not take her.
如果你带走了她
If you have taken her，
请让她回来
you will give her back.
让她回来...
Give her back...
让她回来，求求?
Give her back，please. Please.
我以为命运会眷顾你，嗯？
I expected fate to put up more of a fight，eh？
是我被击倒的话
I will not have that smile on your face
我肯定笑不出来
as I strike you down.
爱德华汀奇，转头看吧
Take a gander，Edward Teach.
这块土地永远属于光荣的
This land is hereby forever claimed in the glorious name
乔治王陛下名下...
of His Majesty King George...
你的勇敢将载入史册
Someone make a note of that man's bravery.
小姐，圣盃，请拿给我
Senorita，the chalices，por favor.
只有上帝能赐予永生
Only God can grant eternal life，
不是这个异教之泉
not this pagan water.
摧毁这座异教寺院！
Men，destroy this profane temple！
不老泉！
The Fountain！
你是个笨蛋
You are a fool.
你在这里寻找的
You seek in this place what
只有信仰才能给你
only faith can provide.
信仰？
Faith？
的确，可以光明的让你看见
In faith，there is light enough to see
但也可以黑暗的让你失明
but darkness enough to blind.
这是什么妖术？
What devilry is this？
这是为了黑珍珠号
For the Pearl.
你做了什么？
What have you done？
安洁莉卡！不要！剑有毒！
Angelica！Don't！It's poison！
我不会傻到没有一点优势
I'm not such the fool to take on Blackbeard
就来抓黑胡子的
without a little venomous advantage.
杰克！
Jack！
我宣布黑胡子的船和船员
I claim Blackbeard's ship and crew，
以及这把剑
and this sword，
赔偿我失去的腿！
payment for my missing limb！
抓好了！拉！
Hang on！Pull！
别浪费了我的泪水
Do not waste my tear.
喝下这杯
Drink this.
这杯有人鱼泪水
This one has the tear.
你必须喝另一杯
You must drink the other.
不！
No！
你们俩没法同时救
I cannot save you both.
你们得牺牲一个
One of you must sacrifice.
你喝吧，父亲，救赎你的灵魂
You take it，Father，for your soul.
汀奇船长，她快死了
Captain Teach，she's dying.
你得救你的女儿
You must save your daughter.
这杯是死？
This one takes life？
这杯是生？
This one has the tear and gives life？
对，快喝啊！
Aye，hurry！
安洁莉卡...我的女儿，救救我
Angelica...Save me，my child.
不
No.
父亲，我爱你
I love you，Father.
等等
Wait a minute.
我好像弄反了
In fact，it might have been the other way around.
这杯才有泪水
This cup had the tear，
你喝的那杯没有
that one had the other bit.
骗子！
Trickster！
恶魔！
Devil！
父亲！
Father！
混蛋！你怎么可以这样？
You bastard！How could you？
你的父亲救了你
Your father saved you.
也许他的灵魂得到救赎了，嗯？
Perhaps his soul is now redeemed，eh？
你受伤了
You are hurt.
只是肉体
In body only.
我的心灵很平静...
My mind is at peace...
因为你
because of you.
我？
Me？
对
Yes.
我曾经迷失
I was lost.
海风，潮汐...
The wind，the tides...
...它们应该可以使人恢复信仰
...they ought to renew a man's faith.
但使我恢复信仰的，只有你
But for me，only you.
菲利浦，我可以救你
Philip，I can save you.
只要你要求我
You need only ask.
我只要求一件事
I seek but one thing.
什么事？
What is that？
宽恕
Forgiveness.
要不是我
If not for me，
你不会被抓住
you would never have been captured.
要求吧
Ask.
原谅我？
Forgive me？
我恨你
I hate you.
救过你命的笨蛋？
The bloke who saved your life？
我拥有的岁月
The years I possess，
偷窃自我的父亲！
stolen from my own father！
我只是帮黑胡子
I only helped Blackbeard do what
尽了父亲该做的事
any father should have done.
你既残忍又无知
You are cruel and ignorant.
一把手枪，一颗子弹
One pistol，one shot.
在我饿死前自杀？
To kill myself before I starve？
亲爱的，我信不过你
There's no trusting you，love.
再说，这是繁忙的贸易路线
Besides，this is a well-traveled trade route.
你可以给经过的船只打信号
You can signal a passing ship.
或者你可以饮弹自尽，随你便
Or you can just bite the proverbial bullet，as it were.
那我又要怎么挣脱这些绳索？
And how will I get free of these bonds？
半个小时前你就挣脱绳索了
You broke free of your bonds half an hour ago，
正在想着怎么样向我发动袭击
waiting for the precise moment to pounce.
杰克，承认吧
Admit it，Jack.
你还爱着我
You still love me.
如果你有妹妹和一只狗
If you had a sister and a dog，
我会选择那只狗
I'd choose the dog.
宝藏！有个装满珠宝的箱子！
Treasure！There is a chest with jewels！
珠宝拥有控制风向和潮汐的力量！
Jewels with the power to rule the wind and tide！
你在乱掰！
You're making that up！
等等...
Wait...
我怀孕了
I am with child.
是你的
Yours.
我不记得我们有过...
I don't recall that we ever had...
那次你喝醉了！
You were drunk！
我从没醉到那种程度
I've actually never been that drunk.
等等！
Wait！
我有些话想对你说
There is something I want to say to you.
从一见面起我就想说
Something I wanted to say from the moment we first met.
说吧
Go on，then.
我爱你
I love you.
我也爱你
As do I.
永远都爱
Always have.
永远不变
Always will.
我得走了
I gotta go.
杰克！
Jack！
我跟你还没完！
This is not over！
杰克！
Jack！
打偏啦！
Missed！
这个“复仇”属于我
The Revenge is mine.
先生...
Sir...
我们在甲板下发现这个
We found this below decks.
全体船员！迎风航行！
All hands！Ply to windward！
扬起船帆，你们这些蟑螂！
Get cracking，ye blooming cockroaches！
虽然国王待我不薄
The Crown served me well.
不过现在，以海神及天神之名...
But now，by the gods of sea and sky...
...向龟岛全速前进！
...make way for Tortuga！
吉卜斯，你这邪恶，糊涂的醉鬼
Gibbs，you filthy，besotted shellback
你搞定啦！
you made it！
对啊！
Aye！
我相信我们联手
And I trust we managed a profit
成功了是不是？
from our joint enterprise？
睁亮你的眼睛
Feast your eyes.
罗盘指引我的方向很正确
The compass led me straight and true.
那黑胡子看船的手下呢？
What of Blackbeard's men guarding the ship？
我用新几内亚的绝招摆平了
I employed the selfsame maneuver we perfected in New Guinea.
没弄走全部舰队有点可惜
Seemed a shame to leave an entire fleet behind.
是有点可惜
Shame indeed.
我讨厌那只猴子
I hate that monkey.
黑珍珠号...要怎样把她弄出来？
So，the Pearl...Any idea how to get her out？
需要一把十字弓
We shall need a crossbow，
一个砂时计，三只山羊
an hourglass，three goats.
一人念咒语同时
One of us must learn to play the trumpet whilst
另一人装神弄鬼...
the other one goes like this...
我认识一个有山羊的人
I know a man with a goat.
你把山羊弄来，我擅长装神弄鬼
Good. I can go like this.
杰克，我不明白...
Jack，I have to ask...
你有了圣盃
You had the chalices，
不老泉，人鱼泪水...
the water，the tear...
你大可以拥有永生的
You could have lived maybe forever.
不老泉是一个考验，吉卜斯
The Fountain does test you，Gibbs.
永远不要妄图知道
But better to not know
自己的生命终点
which moment may be your last.
生命的奥义
Every morsel of your entire being
就是活在当下
alive to the infinite mystery of it all.
谁说我就不能永生，嗯？
And who's to say I won't live forever，eh？
我是不老泉的发现者耶
Discoverer of the Fountain of Youth.
我本身就成为一个传奇了，吉卜斯
I have no say in it，Gibbs.
我是个不折不扣的海盗
It's a pirate's life for me.
了了？
Savvy？